As we keep adding features to our health insurance plan,
its premium will also keep increasing.
After adding all the features and benefits of our need, when we look
at its price, we get shocked.
How will we be able to afford such an expensive health insurance plan? Therefore, in today's
video, I have brought such a health
insurance plan for you which will give
you good coverage at a very reasonable price.
I am talking
about My Health Care Plan. In this plan,
you get many special features inbuilt,
such as maternity expenses, that is, the
delivery expenses of a new born baby, whether it
is a normal delivery or a C-section delivery, its
expenses are covered inbuilt in this plan.
New born baby will also get coverage, that is,
if any complication occurs between the birth of the child and the age of 90 days, then
that coverage
is also inbuilt in this plan. Along with this, there is
also inbuilt coverage of consumables, that is, the
non-medical items.  There's
no need to worry,
this plan also covers OPD
expenses, meaning those who need to see a doctor without being admitted
and prescribed diagnostic tests.
These expenses can also be
covered in this plan without any add-ons. This
plan is inbuilt in this plan. Not only this,
home nursing charges can also be claimed.
After receiving any treatment and after the claim is
approved, when we return home
and nursing services are taken there,
you can also claim such expenses under this plan.
But
my purpose in making this video is to explain the
benefits of this plan to you in
depth instead of explaining it superficially at the surface level, that is,
who can take this plan,
what features and
benefits will you get under this plan, and
what terms and conditions have been imposed on them, which will be
very useful for you while making a claim.
Apart from this, you will also know the waiting period in detail, that is,
which treatment is
covered after how much time, and most importantly,
how much will we get this plan, this policy, that is,
its  We will also know what the pricing is
now because we never compromise on the
quality of information in our videos, so
this video may also be a
little long and hence I
also expect some patience from you, so why
delay, let's start this video, first of all we will
understand what are the eligibility conditions for
taking Bajaj Allians My Health Care Plan, so the
first
point we will discuss here is the entry age,
if we talk about it then the minimum entry age
is 18 years and the maximum entry age is 65
years, however, I think that
after the latest guidelines of IRDA, this maximum
age capping will be removed and if we
talk about dependent child, then from 90
days of age till 30 years of age dependent
child can be the part of this policy with
their parents, now how many types of policy types can you
take, so here you can take
individual policy i.e. for yourself alone,
multi individual policy i.e. for your family
members but for everyone  The sum insured will be
different and along with this you
can also take a family floater policy in which the
entire combined family is covered together
but the sum insured is common for all and is
on a floater basis. So,
you can also take such a family floater policy under this plan. There is
no age limit for renewal. You can get this policy renewed for life
long. And if we talk about the sum
insured, that is, how much treatment can you
cover in this policy, then those
options are also quite flexible. Starting
from ₹ 3 lakh of sum insured, you can choose up
to ₹ crore of sum insured having
multiple options in between. And
so we understood, but is it
necessary to get a medical test done to take this plan?
This is necessary only in certain conditions.
If the entry age of the policy holder is
more than 46 years and his sum insured is
more than ₹ lakh, then in such a case, a pre-policy
medical checkup will be done, that is, the medical
test will have to be done if the age is also less. The sum
insured  It is also less but if the policy holder has
any adverse medical condition which
he declares as a PD, then also the
insurance company can ask the policy holder to get these
tests done.
Now after knowing who
can take this policy, we will know
what expenses will be covered under this plan after taking the policy
and what are the limits on them. The
first point is the room rent limit, that is,
which category of room can the policy holder take during the treatment, it
depends on your sum insured, that is,
how much policy amount you have chosen. If
your policy is from ₹ lakh to ₹ lakh, then
you can choose up to a single private AC room
during treatment, but if the sum is
more than this, that is, if you have chosen the sum insured from ₹ 1 lakh to ₹ crore, then
you can choose any category of room. If you have a
policy of this sum insured, then there is
no capping on the room rent. Pre
and post hospitalization expenses, that is  If
we get admitted to a hospital for some treatment, the
claim gets approved.
60 days of pre-
hospitalization and 90 days of post-
hospitalization expenses related to this treatment after the patient has been
discharged from the hospital. 190
days of post-hospitalization expenses can be
covered in Bajaj My Healthcare Plan. Will
organ donor coverage be available? That is, if a
policy holder has to undergo an organ transplant, then
organ donor
coverage is definitely covered under this plan and there is
no capping on it up to the sum
insured. This coverage will be available only.
If you take AYUSH treatment i.e.
Ayurveda, Yoga and Naturopathy, Unani,
Siddha and Homeopathy alternative treatment,
then there is no capping on this also.
How much road ambulance expenses can be claimed?
This is also based on actuals. If
your treatment claim is approved, then the
road ambulance expenses will be covered as per actuals, that is,
you can claim only the amount you have spent on using the ambulance.
Now let's talk about
maternity expenses, that is, up
to what amount can the child birth expenses be
claimed and
what are the terms and conditions associated with it. If your sum insured is
₹3 lakh or more, then you will
not get maternity coverage under this plan. The minimum sum
insured should be ₹5 lakh and if your
sum insured is ₹1 lakh to ₹1 lakh, then you
can cover maternity expenses and delivery expenses of a maximum of ₹10,000.
And if your sum insured is ₹15 lakh to ₹1 lakh,
you can cover up to ₹75,000 of delivery
expenses. And if your sum insured is
more than this, that is, about ₹1 lakh, then you will be able to
claim delivery expenses up to ₹1 lakh. There are
some conditions related to maternity expenses which are important to know.
Only two deliveries are covered in the entire policy lifetime.  This
can be done and the
age of the policy holder should be
less than 45 years to take this maternity claim.
Waiting period is also applicable but
what is the waiting period for maternity,
we will understand that in the section on waiting period.
Now comes the turn to understand the new born baby
coverage, that is, if the insured
person gives birth to a new born baby, then from the
birth of that child
till 90 days of age, that child will
get new born baby coverage. If there is any
complication and the child has to be
admitted, then his treatment will also be
covered but there are some limits in this. The extent to which
this treatment can be covered will
also depend on your sum insured.
If your policy is of ₹3 lakh or
₹1 lakh, you can cover new born baby
coverage up to ₹1 lakh and if your sum
insured is 5 to ₹10 lakh, you get a
new born baby coverage of ₹1 lakh if ​​the
sum insured of your policy is ₹1 lakh.  If the sum insured is between 15 lakh and 50 lakh, then
you will get newborn baby coverage of ₹10 lakh.
And if your sum
insured is above ₹1 lakh, then you get
newborn baby coverage of ₹1 lakh
inbuilt in the plan. Now comes a
very special feature of the plan that is OPD
related expenses i.e. Out Patient
Department expenses, in which we
go to the doctor for diagnosis and
there too we incur expenses. There is the
cost of seeing the doctor and diagnostic
tests are prescribed for diagnosis, so
you can claim their expenses also in this policy. The
amount is your policy
premium. You will get two times the amount of that premium in your wallet, that is,
your points will come in your wallet.
You can redeem these points for OPD consultations
and diagnostic tests. The
first feature of this plan is teleconsultation.
You can do a maximum of 15 teleconsultations in a month and once with the
doctor with whom you are consulting.
You will be able to change the doctor only after that consultation is over. The
second feature is of in-clinic
consultation, that is, you physically go to your doctor and
visit them, you
can also visit doctors by going to Bajaj Allianz's cashless network hospital and
you will be able to do a maximum of 15 consultations in these clinics within the entire month, but the
limit of consultations is that you can utilize up to
50% of the total amount in your wallet,
where you will be able to utilize the remaining 50%. You
can also get diagnostic tests done. If a
doctor has prescribed some tests for you after diagnosis,
then you can
cover the cost of getting these tests done in this policy, the
maximum limit on this is
also 50% of the wallet amount, you will be
able to use it and the final coverage which comes in OPD expenses
is annual preventive
health check-ups, that is, we
can get some tests done free of cost throughout the year,
for that you will get a voucher for that throughout the year,
which you can use.  It is
very important to have modern treatments on a cashless basis in today's health insurance policies for getting health checkup tests done. Is
this coverage available under this plan? Yes, it is.
All the 12 listed modern treatments are covered by IRDA in this plan. The
special thing is that there is
no capping on any treatment. Day
treatment means the treatment for which the policy
holder does not have to be admitted
to the doctor and the day treatment procedure is done, then
that is also
covered in this policy. The important thing to keep in mind is
that this day care procedure should
not be done in the OPD. Either it should be done
in a day care center or in
a hospital as inpatient hospitalization, only then
this day care procedure will be covered.
Home nursing benefit, which
I also mentioned in the introduction of this video,
if a policy holder has
taken treatment under this policy, the claim is
approved, they are discharged
and nursing is required for post-hospitalization care, then
these nursing
charges can also be claimed, but on a
weekly basis.  You will get it and according to your sum
insured, if the
sum insured of your policy is up to ₹ 5000000, then it is
for ₹ 5000000. If your sum insured of
this policy is more than ₹ 1000000, that is, if you have
couches for walking,
wheelchair, cane, braces, then this
type of coverage can also be taken. According to your sum
insured, ₹ 2000000 and 0000 can be
covered in this plan. Now comes the turn to
discuss the sum insured restoration,
that is, it can also be called restoration benefit.
If the sum insured of your base policy is
completely exhausted, then
how many times will you get restoration? If your
policy is for ₹ 3 and ₹ lakh and the sum insured is this much, then
restoration will happen only once in a year
up to 100% of sum insured. But
if your policy is of 5  If the sum insured is ₹50 lakh and above,
your restoration benefit will be
unlimited times in a year up to 100% of the
sum insured. However, there is a hidden condition
to be kept in mind. If the sum insured is used during any treatment, the
restoration benefit is used,
and within 15 days, if the same treatment for the
same medical condition lapses and
money is required for the treatment again, then the
restoration benefit will not work. That is,
once the restoration benefit is
over, there must be a gap of 15 days
for the same treatment and for the same person.
If there is another policy member, he
can use it. If there is any other treatment, it can be
used for that,
but a gap of 15 days for the same treatment
is mandatory. You will also get airlift cover as a
standard benefit under this plan.
If your sum insured is ₹50 lakh and ₹1
crore, then you will get airlift cover of ₹10
lakh. And if  If your sum insured is now ₹1
crore, then ₹1 lakh of airlift cover you can
claim in this policy. How much will be the cumulative bonus, that is,
how much will your sum insured increase if you do not claim every year. It also
depends on your sum insured. For how many rupees have
you taken the policy. If your policy is of ₹
3 and 44 lakh, then your
cumulative bonus will increase by 25 percent every
year, that is, your cumulative bonus will almost
double within the next 4 years. It will
increase by 25 percent every year. But if your
policy is for sum insured of ₹1 lakh or more, then
your cumulative bonus will
increase by 50 percent every year, that is,
your sum insured will double within 2 years
because 100% is your sum insured and
you will get 100% cumulative bonus. Family visit is
also a feature in this plan, that is,
any policy holder can avail the benefits given in his policy.
If a person faces a medical emergency 200 km away from his/her residential address
and has to be admitted
after an accident or any other
emergency, then
economy fare will be given for one immediate family member from his/her home.
To and fro fare i.e.
travel fare will be given and its limit
is also linked to your sum insured. If
your policy is up to ₹10 lakh, then the maximum
limit for this family visit is ₹2500000
Sum Insured Then your maximum limit for
family visit cover will be ₹5000000. The next
feature we will discuss is renewal premium
waiver i.e. next year's premium will be waived. The
proposer of this policy, who makes
its payment, takes tax deduction.
If the proposer of this policy dies
in an accident or due to any such reason, then the
premium for the next year will be
waived. The policy will continue
but the premium will not be charged from this family.
Coverage is available, meaning
non-medical items will also be
covered as a standard feature under this plan. There
is a sum limit on cataract, which is
important to discuss.
If you get treatment for cataract,
if your policy is up to ₹10 lakh sum
insured, then your sub-limit is
% of sum insured and income on ₹1 lakh.
You can claim % of your sum insured or ₹1 lakh for one eye operation. And
if the sum insured is more than ₹1 lakh or
you have taken a policy for more than ₹1 lakh, then there will be
no such limit on cataract treatment. Now friends, till now
you have understood the standard features of Bajaj My Healthcare. There are
optional covers as well, which also
need to be discussed. The first optional
cover, which is an add-on, which you can avail by
paying extra money, is loss of income.
If a policy holder is hospitalized
due to which they  If there is loss of income, they
can compensate for that too. The
compensation for the number of weeks will be decided according to the number of days of hospitalization. You can decide how much
money you will get per week while choosing this add-on. The
premium will be charged from you accordingly.
What will be the options - 10,000, 20,000 and 25,000
per week compensation. You can choose
while taking this add-on. The next add-on is
Major Illness and Accident Multiplier. If
any of the 10 listed critical illnesses
is diagnosed or any
accidental injury occurs, then the
sum insured will automatically double. In these two
cases only, if there are 10 listed critical illnesses
or an accident occurs, then your sum
insured will double if you take this add-on. The
final and third add-on is
International coverage, that is,
if you
want to take coverage outside India geographical limits.  So, with co-payments,
you can cover that too, but you will have to take this
add-on for international coverage.
You can see more details related to this
in the policy terms document. Now,
before I tell you
about some important discounts available in this policy, i.e.
how you can reduce your premium, let us
quickly understand the waiting period and
after how much time which treatment will be covered.
First of all, the initial waiting period is 30
days, which means you will not get any coverage except accidental treatment within the first 30 days of taking the policy.
If you have
ported or migrated the policy, then this
waiting period gets waived. The second
waiting period is specific diseases, that is,
listed illnesses and listed procedures,
you will get coverage for them after 24 months.
And talking about pre-existing diseases, that is, at the
time of taking the policy, any policyholder declares that he has a
medical condition
and the insurance company accepts it and
gives him this policy, then it is 36 months.
Will be covered after 36 months Next
waiting period is related to maternity, that is,
after how much time will the baby delivery charges be covered The waiting
period is 36 months but you can also reduce it
If you take a 3 year policy and a long
term policy together, then your
waiting period will be reduced by 1 year, the waiting
period will be 2 years Along with this,
you will also get a long term discount on 8 out of 8 The
same thing is with the new born baby cover The
waiting period is 36 months
but if you take a long term policy for three
years, this waiting period will be reduced
to 2 years Now friends, let's discuss how many types of discounts
you can get in Bajaj Allianz My Health Care Plan
Discounts Although many options are given in the policy,
but I will tell you about the four-five
most common discounts The
first discount is the zone
based discount The entire
premium will be charged within zone A If your
address as per the address proof
falls in zone B, then you will get the discount in zone A  You will
get a discount of 15% on the premium of Rs. 15% and
if you come in Zone C, which are listed
cities and states,
then you will get a discount of 25% on the premium of Zone A. There is
no zone based copayment,
but the premium will be
charged according to the zone. The second
discount is online discount.
If you buy this policy online
directly from Bajaj's website or any other
online platform, then you will
get a discount of 5%. After this, the third
discount is loyalty
discount. If you have
any other policy of Bajaj Allianz related to any product, be it
your car insurance, bike
insurance, property insurance, fire
insurance, any Bajaj Allianz policy,
and its premium is more than Rs. 2500,
if you present that policy, then
you will get an extra discount of 5% as loyalty discount. Along with this, there is
also an early entry discount.
If you buy this plan before 35 years of age,
then
you will also get an early entry discount of 5%. Apart from this, there are
many other types of discounts like
you can avail wellness discount.  This means
you can earn discounts even by maintaining a healthy lifestyle.
Along with this,
we have already discussed the discount on long term policy.
Now friends, here
comes the final part of the video. Let us know
about
Bajaj's policy because we are also
considering maternity. The age of the first adult member
is 30 years and the age of the second adult member is
27 years. I am taking sum insured of
₹ 155 lakhs in Zone A and I will
tell you the prices for all three members. Zone A is
for big cities, so here I have taken sum insured of
₹ 1 lakh for this family
size. For Zone B and C, I am going to tell you the premium for ₹ 10
lakh sum insured.
So, for this family, for ₹ 15
lakh coverage for Zone A, they have to pay ₹ 5884 on an annual basis.
And if we talk about coverage of ₹ 10
lakh for Zone B, then the same family will have to pay ₹
1740.  It will be Rs
8740 i.e. they have to pay annually for Rs 10 lakh of
coverage and if we talk about Zone C for Rs 10 lakh
coverage, this family will have to pay
Rs
1,335 only for annual policy coverage in Bajaj
and My Health Care Plan. Now these prices which
I have told you are online prices,
these are as of today, it is possible that
some changes may come in them later. If
you are watching this video in future, then
you can contact the insurance company for real time prices,
otherwise you will get the estimate,
you will get an idea of ​​how much this
policy will cost. The coverage in the plan is quite
good, the prices are also reasonable, but the
number of days of pre and post hospitalization
seems less to me comparatively with
other plans. Now see, there is maternity
coverage, you get consumer bill cover,
OPD coverage, but the number
I found the pre- and post-hospitalization expenses of this plan to be slightly lower. The
rest of the overall plan is fine.
My purpose in making this video was to give you a
completely transparent
and in-depth review of this plan so that you can understand
each and every feature, benefit, and
point of this plan very well. How did you like this
video?
You can share your review in the comment section.
Please do let us know how you liked this plan by commenting. To show your love and support,
you can like the video
and wherever necessary, please share
it with anyone who needs this video or this information.
The plan I have mentioned to you today has
reasonable prices,
but this is not the case with every health insurance plan. There are
some health insurance
plans on which if you do
not file a claim, their premium will not
increase. The premium will remain the same, which provides you a lot of
savings and also makes your health
insurance plan inflation-proof.
If you want to know
which health insurance plans are available and
what features are inside them, then you can check this.
Please watch the video, I have given complete information in it,
I, Harvinder Singh, now
take your permission, I will get it from you in the next video, till then take
care of yourself,
stay happy and stay healthy, Jai Hind